<Document>
  # The Mansus Veil Weakens
  So you're a Heretic? Well, get ready for magic and battle. Grab influences, complete sacrifices, accomplish rituals, and ascend to godhood.

  Your ultimate goal is to ascend and become all powerful, but to do that you must gain knowledge.
  In order to ascend, you must complete your objectives, research final ascension knowledge and perform ascension ritual on transmutation rune.

  To start, you need to choose a path, currently there are six paths:
  - The [textlink="Ashen Path" link="AshPath"]: Focuses on fire, damage over time, and early mobility. Great for new heretics.
  - The [textlink="Path of Void" link="VoidPath"]: Focuses on cold, silence, and stealth. Also great for new heretics.
  - The [textlink="Path of Flesh" link="FleshPath"]: Focuses on necromancy and summoning. Good for heretics that want friends.
  - The [textlink="Path of Lock" link="LockPath"]: Focuses on mobility, access, and stealth. Good for heretics that want to be sneaky.
  - The [textlink="Rusted Path" link="RustPath"]: Focuses on area control, and rapid healing. Good for heretics that want to be extremely tanky.
  - The [textlink="Path of Blade" link="BladePath"]: Focuses on sheer melee power. Good for heretics that want a bloodbath.
  - The [textlink="Path of Cosmos" link="CosmosPath"]: Focuses on teleportation and confusion! A very difficult heretic path to master.

  [textlink="Click here to see more information and list of starting and side knowledge" link="HereticRituals"]

  After choosing your path; it's time to gather your first influences, this can be done in three ways.
  - Sacrificing crew members your dark patrons hunger for.
  - Automatically getting one knowledge point every 20 minutes.
  - Draining influences that spawn randomly after you complete a sacrifice.

  ## Eldritch Influences
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EldritchInfluence" Caption="Eldritch Influence"/>
  </Box>
  Influences are the easy way to gain power points. Anytime a heretic completes a sacrifice, influences will randomly spawn across the station.
  They are not visible to the naked eye of a crew member, however they [bold]will[/bold] become visible after harvesting, aside from suddenly changing colors.
  Influences give 1 knowledge point when harvested normally, and can be harvested with either [color=green]Codex Cicatrix[/color] or [color=green]Codex Morbus[/color] to get a knowledge point in addition to a free side knowledge.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EldritchInfluenceSpent" Caption="Harvested influence. Notice the glow."/>
  </Box>

  Each influence can only be harvested once, so try to get them before other heretics, even if that means killing other heretics.

  ## Transmutation is Key
  Eventually, you'll need to start using proper magics. To draw a transmutation rune, you'll need a writing tool, such as a pen or crayon.
  Activate [color=green]Mansus Grasp[/color] in your offhand and click on the floor to start drawing a rune.
  These runes are highly noticeable and take up a 3x3 area.
  You can freely remove runes by using your pen with the activated [color=green]Mansus Grasp[/color] on it, and you can also freely use other Heretic's runes.

  To [bold]transmute[/bold], simply click the rune with your empty hand to choose the needed ritual, after that use your [color=green]Mansus Grasp[/color] on the rune to see what objects you require for the ritual.
  You can always see your chosen ritual by [bold]inspecting[/bold] the rune.

  Transmutation Rituals allow you to create powerful artifacts, demonic monsters, and many useful tools that will help you progress towards ultimate power.

  ## Sacrifices
  The primary method for getting knowledge is by sacrificing crewmates.
  The Mansus desires only a select few Heathens (non-heretics) at any moment.

  At the start of the round you will be assigned four-five sacrifice targets.

  - One target will be a Head of Staff.
  - One target will be a member of Security.
  - Other targets will be completely random crewmembers.

  Sacrificing a Head of Staff or member of security will reward you 3 knowledge points, sacrificing any other crewmember will reward 2. You cannot sacrifice regular non-target crewmembers.

  Other heretics are an exception. You can always sacrifice another heretic and get 3 knowledge points for doing so.

  Follow your [color=red]Living Heart[/color] to your target of choice and incapacitate them through any means necessary. If your target is incapacitated, they're ready to sacrifice.
  Drag them over a transmutation rune and invoke the [color=yellow]Sacrifice[/color] to sacrifice them.

  First, drag a body on the rune, then select the ritual by clicking the rune with an empty hand. Then click on the rune with your Mansus Grasp to invoke the ritual and sacrifice the body.

  You can reroll your targets by invoking [color=yellow]Relentless Heartbeat[/color] ritual.

  ## Mansus Grasp

  A powerful spell that garbles target speech, knocks them down and deals 80 stamina damage. It has additional effects based on your chosen path.

  [color=red]Important:[/color] Mansus Grasp cannot be used by clicking a mob using context menu. But it works in [color=red]Combat Mode[/color], Left click in combat mode only affects mobs, and right click acts like left click, but affects everything. Note that Mansus Grasp cannot miss.

  ## The Heretic Blade

  The Sickly Blade will be your first unlocked research. It can be created by transmuting a common knife (this includes even Shivs, which are made by wrapping Glass Shards with Cloth) with a secondary ingredient based on your path, and serves as a powerful melee weapon as well as a one time use escape tool.

  All paths have their own kind of blade, which only differ in appearance and name without any additional research. As with the Mansus Grasp, your blade will be upgraded by your research over time. Said upgrades will differ depending on the path you choose.

  You are limited in the amounts of blades you can create at a time - most paths limit you to two blades, and Blade limits you to four.

  Additionally, you can break your blade by activating it in-hand to teleport to a random, (mostly) safe location in a pinch. Better to lose your weapon and live another day than die fighting. The ability to blade break is lost once your Path Robes are crafted or you accrue 10 knowledge points or research Blade upgrade.

  ## Passive Abilities

  Upon selecting a path, the Heretic will receive a passive ability that can be upgraded a couple of times.

  Crafting your robes upgrades your passive to Tier 2, which unlocks the Ritual of Knowledge. This ritual requires a set of random items; completing it grants 4 Knowledge Points and the final passive upgrade.

  ## Heretical Research
  Once you have some power points, it's time to research! Open up your knowledge store using the action button.
  The research menu forms a branching tree, and your first selection will be to commit to a path that defines your abilities and Final Ascension.
  You can learn side knowledge available to all paths, but overall your chosen path will heavily influence your play-style.

  ## Focus is Necessary
  To cast more advanced spells, you must focus by wearing an [color=orange]Amber Focus[/color].
  You can acquire Amber Focus using the eponymous ritual.
  Some more powerful heretical equipment also functions as a focus - namely, the Ominous Armor from the Armorer's Ritual (when the hood is flipped up).
  [color=yellow]Ascension[/color] disables the need for a focus.

  ## Point of No Return: The Heretic Aura

  This is the most important turning point for any Heretic. When you either craft your [bold]Path-Specific Robes[/bold] or accrue [bold]10 knowledge points[/bold] or researching [bold]Path-Specific Blade Upgrade[/bold] (whichever comes first), the following permanent changes occur:

  - You lose the ability to Blade Break (emergency teleport by activating blade in-hand).
  - You gain a permanent visible aura that identifies you as a Heretic to everyone. This makes you valid to kill.

  If you choose [color=yellow]Feast of Owls[/color] (reject ascension for points) or pick the [color=purple]Lock Path[/color], you will not receive the aura.

Once the aura appears, there is no hiding what you are. Plan accordingly.

  ## The Chaplain
  A powerful foe indeed, try to steer clear of the Chaplain! Their Null Rod and it's variants will block magic and deal holy damage to you while you're wielding heretical equipment!

  Heretics can heal holy damage a few ways:
  - Standing on a transmutation rune.
  - Standing on rust as rusted path heretic.
  - Being near raw prophets as flesh heretic.
  - Drinking from the Eldritch Flask.
  - Using Nightwatcher's Rebirth ashen path ability.
  - Hitting living people with your blades as ascended blade heretic.

  ## Tips
  - All heretic blades penetrate armor to some extent, trigger marks, and can be used in hand to teleport away from danger.
  - Your Mansus Grasp will temporarily garble the speech of people who you use it on. This can let you get away with murder while comms are online. It also breaks their suit sensors temporarily, making them invisible on crew monitors.
  - Your blade and your mark act as surgery tools. You can use them to extract organs from people or heal yourself as a last resort.
  - Your blade creation ritual has a limited amount of blades you can create. 2 for most paths and 4 for blade path. Performing this ritual again, while limit is reached, will instead teleport one of your lost blades on the transmutation rune.
  - Need vomit for rituals? Spin or do a flip multiple times in a quick succession to make yourself vomit.
  - You can enchant items using your Codex Cicatrix and Transmutation rune. [textlink="For more info on enchanting, click here." link="Enchanting"]
  - Be wary of other heretics. They worship false gods, and will sacrifice you for knowledge just as easily as they would any other heathen. However, you can sacrifice them to the Mansus as well. Let the strongest god win.
  - As a [color=purple]Raw Prophet[/color], your [color=green]Mansus Link[/color] ability is extremely useful for communication. When you use it on someone, they gain a hivemind similar to changelings with +m key to talk privately.
  - [color=purple]Influences[/color] can spawn in almost any location on the station, ranging from the main hallways and public restrooms to [color=cyan]Command staff offices[/color] and [color=red]restricted security areas[/color] in the Brig. It's best to check every area you can access, public and department.
  - Monkeys and other animals make for great, usually non-suspicious sources of organs or corpses for your heretical rituals.
  - Most summoned ghouls will drop organs on death. While having them to die is not ideal, you can easily grab the parts and summon another.
  - [color=yellow]Eldritch Flask[/color], a Tier 1 side path knowledge acts like a cryostasis beaker and has a total capacity of 100 units, meaning you can create deadly mixes that are easily triggered.
</Document>
