<Document>
  # Nullrod Forms
  Nullrods can be transformed to unique forms by using them on an altar.

  ## Altar replacement
  Altars can be set to fit your desired look by applying a required item to the base altar, you can remove the applied item to return the altar to base form using a crowbar.
  WARNING: Nullrod transformation is a non-reversible process, so choose wisely.

  ## Nullrod
  Old reliable, the nullrod you will arrive on station with. Typically changed out from instantly due to having no special ability, but using it is a real flex of how robust you are.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Nullrod"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarConvert"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Crowbar"/>
  </Box>

  ## Arrythmic Knife
  Provides the user with a randomized movespeed boost periodically. Could help you chase down an unholy enemy, but could also slow you to a crawl while you try to escape.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ArrythmicKnife"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarFangs"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMeatBacon"/>
  </Box>

  ## Bulwark
  Stand as the lord protector. A truely powerful shield capable of blocking all hostile attacks when positioned on a tile. Additonally can be used to dash a short distance periodically, which will knockback and harm anyone hit along the way.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Bulwark"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarConvertBlue"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MakeshiftShield"/>
  </Box>

  ## Casul and Jackal
  A pair of holy pistols and a snazzy belt to store them in. Can only be fired together. Pray to reload.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingBeltHolsterFilledChaplain"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponPistolCasul"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponPistolJackal"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarTechnology"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MicroManipulatorStockPart"/>
  </Box>

  ## Faith
  A dinky pistol that heals people with bullets, don't ask. Applies holy damage to unholy enemies with the same bullets. Pray to reload.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponPistolFaith"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarConvertWhite"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="IngotSilver1"/>
  </Box>

  ## God Hand
  God's blessing to his most trusted chaplain. Applies fire and holyfire stacks on attack. Has the same pry ability as a crowbar. Unremovable.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GodHand"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarChaos"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetPlasma1"/>
  </Box>

  ## Grey Emperor's Glove
  Lead the tider's to gods light. An unremovable insulated hand with most every tool you would require to lead the greytide. Use item in-hand to cycle through tool selection.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UristHand"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarConvertMaint"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHandsGlovesColorYellowBudget"/>
  </Box>

  ## Honkmother's Maw
  HONK! A huge clown mask imbued with the power of the honkmother. Knocks down on hit. Don't be surprised if the clown steals this from you.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HonkmotherMaw"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarBananium"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MaterialBananium1"/>
  </Box>

  ## Holy Chainsaw
  An unremovable chainsaw. Must be wielded to attack. I mean, it's a chainsaw that does holy damage.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HolyChainsaw"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarToolbox"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToolboxEmergency"/>
  </Box>

  ## Holy Claywmore
  DEUS VULT! Can fire a marking projectile, which upon being attacked will heal brute, asphyxiation and blododloss of the wielder.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HolyClaymore"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarHeaven"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHelmetTemplar"/>
  </Box>

  ## Iradomini
  A powerful crossbow, must be weilded to fire. Fires a single VERY powerful holy arrow, which will disappear after a minute. Takes a long time to reload via prayer, position wisely.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponPistolIradomini"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarConvertOrange"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BowImprovised"/>
  </Box>

  ## Monk Staff
  In simple terms? A big stick. Launch a flurry of attacks to deal stamina damage on hit, very useful for chasing down the unholy.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MonkStaff"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarDruid"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MaterialWoodPlank1"/>
  </Box>

  ## Ratvarian Spear
  Oh? Prefer the old gods? Well heres the nullrod for you. A one-handed spear imbued with the power of ratvar. Can store more chemicals than usual spears, and applies a large amount of holy damage when thrown.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RatvarianSpear"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarClock"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PowerCellSmallPrinted"/>
  </Box>

  ## Rosary
  Support Mains rejoice. Area of Effect heal on pray, but also harms the unholy who are also nearby.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Rosary"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AltarSpaceChristian"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatHoodNunHood"/>
  </Box>

</Document>
