<Document>
# Circuits

Circuits on Trauma Station let you easily make node-based programs that can run from a single item, while controlling up to 16 devices directly.

Compared to basic logic gate items, you can do far more of their basic operations in a single item, but also use strings and numbers instead of just booleans (on and off).

They are heavily inspired by Stationeers' IC10 system, but using nodes instead of MIPS. If you've played around with IC10s you'll know how to use circuits already.

The [bold]integrated circuit[/bold] item itself can be printed at a circuit printer.

## Housings

An integrated circuit doesn't have any kind of power supply by itself, you need to print a [bold]circuit housing[/bold] at an autolathe.

The regular one uses LV power and must be anchored, it also has a power switch you can toggle by right clicking it.

The portable one uses a powercell and can go anywhere, even inside your chest cavity...
As a result of its portability, it also has a much lower range. You may have to figure out how to relay signals to control far away devices, should you need that.

## Circuit Editor Console

You will need this to actually put a program into a circuit.
Print a board and build a computer like normal, then insert your circuit to begin.

# Ports

On the left and right of the main workspace there are your Input and Output ports.
These ports can send and receive signals from devices linked to the circuit's housing.
You can link ports to gates by clicking one then clicking a pin on a gate, or directly to an output port should you need that.

# Gates

In order to actually do anything you have to add gates. Click buttons on the left to add them to the circuit, then move them somewhere nice.

Like ports, gates have their outputs linked by clicking their pins with eachother. If you misclick a pin, just click it again to stop linking from it.

Currently you are limited to 256 gates so you can pretty much go wild.

# Importing / Exporting

You can click Export at the top to export your circuit to a .yml file on your computer.
You can then import a circuit file later to load existing code onto a circuit, very handy.

</Document>
