<Document>

  # Crimes

  # I. Criminal Violations (Law Code CX)

  ### Criminal violations are those that involve the employee themselves becoming classified as a criminal of some kind through their actions. Along with taboo violations, these are the only actual laws that security cadets are expected to learn and remember, and should be prioritized.

  ## No Penalty Criminal Violations:

  - C0: Contraband Possession: Having any item classified as contraband. This usually doesn't have a sentence other than taking away the contraband, but employees may be subject to monitoring and being suspected of being a member of the organization they possessed the contraband from.

  ## Max 3 Minute Timer Criminal Violations:

  - C1: Mail Tampering: Opening mail that is addressed to another employee, or tampering with the mail incurring a loss of funds. Anyone who does this will be considered a thief and be subject to monitoring by security at their discretion.
  - C2: Theft: Taking personal or departmental items without permission. Anyone who does this will be considered a thief and be subject to monitoring by security at their discretion.
  - C3: Recreational Drug Possession, Usage or Sale: Possession, usage, or sale of any recreational drug besides nicotine or alcohol.
  - C4: Vandalism: Purposefully defacing Nanotrasen property in order to lower its aesthetic value.

  ## Max 5 Minute Timer Criminal Violations:

  - C5: Secure Trespass: Trespass into a security or command area.
  - C6: Kidnapping: Using non-lethal means to capture a member of the crew and hold them hostage.
  - C7: Assault Any assault on a member of the crew.
  - C8: Grand Theft: Stealing any high value or importance item.
  - C9: Destruction of Property. This includes killing any of the station-wide "pets" without a good reason.
  - C10: Grand Assault: Any assault on a member of Command, the Captain, or the Nanotrasen Representative, whether the intent is to murder or not.

  ## D-Class Criminal Violations:

  ### These are violations that specifically warrant reducing an employee's job position to Disposable Class, eliminating all their privileges as a normal crew member.

  - C11 Murder: Purposefully killing someone with no intent to revive.
  - C12 Treason: Knowingly allying with or being a member of any organization or cult opposed to Nanotrasen.
  - C13 Prevention of Revival: Hiding bodies or using deception to prevent the revival of someone on the station who has not been given a do not revive order.
  - C14 Breach of Custody: Removal of anyone who has been arrested from a secure area with the intent to free them, or preventing a security officer from making an arrest.
  - C15 Embezzlement: Stealing funding from Nanotrasen for the purpose of self-enrichment.

  # II. Taboo Violations (Law Code TX)

  ### Those who engage in taboo violations open themself up to immidiate execution by security team members.

  ### Security team members should strive to capture alive those who violate taboo for study.

  - T1: Usage of Magic: Demonstrating usage of magic or usage of a magical item.
  - T2: Conspiracy to Unionize: Conspiring with employees to unionize or asking for "workers rights", which are a violation of corporate rights.
  - T3: Possession of Psionic Capabilities: Being capable of powers that mimic magic through the mind itself.
  - T4: Possession of Illegal and dangerous DNA Modification: Commonly known mutations include: changelings, shadowlings, magic organs, or hulk mutations.

  # III. Protocol Violations (Law Code PX)

  ### Protocol violations are generally the least serious and least likely to be punished violations of corporate law.

  ### When and if they are punished is usually at the discretion of the Nanotrasen Representative, who may request an officer from the HoS to help enforce the punishment.

  - P1: Time Theft: Any extended use of company time for purposes other than productive work. This generally means spending 15 minutes or more doing things other than one's job-related duties. The typical punishment is having to repay this time through salvage work, or being placed on a work plan that involves direct supervision.
  - P2: Unsanctioned Social Gatherings:  Attending and organizing parties, weddings, funerals, ect, that have not been written off by management staff.

  # IV. Disciplinary Violations (Law Code DX)

  ### Disciplinary violations are those that may be enforced at the discretion of security personnel or management staff. The typical punishment for them is corporal punishment.

  - D1: Excessive Public Drunkenness: Those who show excessive public drunkenness through vomiting and slurring of words are assumed to be impeding their ability to work.
  - D2: Insubordination: Failure to follow instructions from one's superior is considered insubordination. Their head is allowed to institute corporal punishment through use of a batong to re-instill a sense of discipline within them. In the case of security officers being insubordinate to the Head of Security, insubordination is considered much more severe and additional actions may be taken at the Head of Security's discretion.
  - D3: Disrespecting Corporate Authority: Disrespecting either the company, or a security officer acting on behalf of the company, shall result in swift corporal punishment, as well as a public apology being made. If the employee refuses to apologize for their transgression, more serious punishments such as brig time may be enacted.
  - D4: Departmental Trespassing: Entering a department one does not have access to without explicit approval of a member of that department. Heads of staff can overrule any approvals given by members of their department.

  # V. Special Disciplinary Violations (Law Code SDX)

  ### These are violations specifically by management staff.

  - SD1: Managerial Incompetence: When a command member is deemed incompetent at their job by either a member of CentComm, or by a vote among the heads, they shall be immediately stripped of their head of staff equipment, banished to salvage-work, and considered a D-Class employee from then on.
  - SD2: Insanity: When a command member is deemed as acting "insane" rather than incompetent, such as engaging in excessively silly behavior, they shall be required to submit to either the psychologist or the Chief Medical Officer for a psychological evaluation. They may then either prescribe a treatment plan, have the head of staff committed to the brig, or perform a lobotomy and have them work in salvage.
  - SD3: Conspiracy: Conspiring against the captain to unlawfully seize power without a proper justification shall result in all command members involved being stripped of their head of staff equipment, banished to salvage-work, and considered D-Class employees.

  # VI. Work Agreement Violations (Law Code WX)

  ### These are violations specific to workers who are not employees of Nanotrasen.
  ### This includes visitors, salvagers, and other foreign agents.
  ### Punishment is at the discretion of the officer who finds individuals in violation of the code.

  - W1: Fraternization: Socializing with actual Nanotrasen Employees.
  - W2: Corporate Espionage: Taking proprietary Nanotrasen technology. Contractors should be searched before they get on the shuttle.
  - W3. Solicitation: Offering services to an employee for spesos or favors outside the scope of their contract, such as a mercenary contractor offering to act as a bodyguard for a Nanotrasen employee.
  - W4. Poaching: Trying to get a Nanotrasen employee to join their company.
</Document>
