<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Aidenkrz <aiden@djkraz.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Kira Gbedan <161087999+Verbalase@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Rouge2t7 <81053047+Sarahon@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Space Law
  The charter of corporate rights grants the following rights to Nanotrasen Employees, in order of importance.

  1. The right to follow corporate law.
  2. The right to work towards the greater wealth and prosperity of Nanotrasen.
  3. The right to respect one’s superiors in management and understand the hard work they accomplished to achieve their position.
  4. The right to a Nanotrasen appointed public defender. If no lawyer is currently available, then the security officer who arrested the employee will be appointed as their defender.
  5. The right to not be prosecuted under a C§ 01 offence. This right is waived if the party fails to comply with lawful orders from security officers that resolves this offence.

  ## Treatment Of Prisoners

  The charter of corporate rights grants the following rights to Nanotrasen Prisoners, in order of importance.

  1. The right to medical treatment.
  2. The right to communcations equipment, if not abused.
  3. The right to food and water.
  4. The right to their shift mandated PDA, unless tampered with; in which case a replacement will be issued.
  5. The right to freedom of movement within the designated brig.

  ## Security

  The charter of corporate rights grants the following rights to Security Employees, in order of importance.

  1. The right to search employees posessions on blue or higher alert, and to secure any contraband.
  2. The right to search employees suspected of a crime on any alert, and to secure any contraband.
  3. The right to check and remove any suspected illegal implants from crewmates suspected of possessing one.
  4. The right to implant any crewmate convicted of any crime with tracking and/or mindshield implants.
  5. The right to execute any crewmate refusing a mindshield implant.
  6. The right to waive brig time for corporal punishment, not exceeding critical condition.

  ## Sentencing

  The charter of corporate rights grants the following rights to the Warden, Head of Security, and in their absense other security employees.

  1. The right to sentence crewmates convicted of a crime for an appropriate time in the brig.
  2. The right to extend brig times for trouble caused.
  3. The right to use corporal punishment to retaliate against trouble caused.
  4. The right to the responsibility to preserve the life of all captured terrorists, magic users, and alien creatures for study at centcom.

  ## [color=red][bold]"YOU MAY NOT EXCEED 5 MINUTES AS A BRIG TIME"[/bold][/color]

  ## Any total brig time that adds up to above 5 minutes will be shortened to meet this limit.

  ## If it goes above 20 minutes, you may perma the person.

  ## Crime Listing
  - [textlink="Crime Listing" link="SpaceLawCrimeList"]
</Document>
